<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tableau | Zach Bogart</title>
    <link>/category/tableau/</link>
      <atom:link href="/category/tableau/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Tableau</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/happy_nerd02.png</url>
      <title>Tableau</title>
      <link>/category/tableau/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Tiny Tableau Tricks</title>
      <link>/post/two-tableau-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/two-tableau-tricks/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;I’m not a master of Tableau, so I always am happy to find places where I can get a toehold on it and make it work for me. It is such a powerful tool, but it can be intimidating. Here are three quick things—one big, two small—that helped me out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;color-by-multiple-dimensions&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Color by Multiple Dimensions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was said off-hand in a section of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/course/tableau10-advanced/&#34;&gt;a helpful Udemy course&lt;/a&gt; I was working through and it became a go-to method for plotting things with many nested categories. Super useful to see how things break down visually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simply command click to select two variables and drag them to the color box&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can reorder the grouping of the variables by dragging one above the other in the shelf.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Definitely an example of a feature that is hard to find, but I end up using it all the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;command-click-to-drag-a-variable-copy&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Command Click to Drag a Variable Copy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would often have a setup of rows and columns, but want to filter out some part of one of the variables, or split into pages somehow. Dragging a new variable from the left may mean you have to alter the default aggregate function and that gets annoying (looking at averages, say, and you drag a new one, defaulting to sum). You can command-click-and-drag to solve this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Command-click-and-drag your nice variable to preserve desired aggregations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple but saves a lot of hassle and makes it more fluid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;click-and-hold-to-pan-maps&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Click and Hold to Pan Maps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found maps annoying to navigate, till I learned you can do it all from the mouse. I would go back and forth clicking tools to get the placement right, usually between pan and zoom. Instead of toggling, you can click-and-hold and it will allow you to pan around, and zoom with scrolling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click-hold-and-drag to pan without switching tools&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More fluid interaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;power-tools-are-powerful-if-they-start-to-fade-away&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Power Tools are Powerful If They Start To Fade Away&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a tool is a pain to work with, it gets in the way of why you are using it in the first place. You want to get something done, to do something creative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still amassing these kinds of tricks for all sorts of data-related tools. That way, after some familiarity with a workflow and being comfortable with different tools, they can step aside and work for you rather than against you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;image-credit&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Image Credit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://thenounproject.com/search/?q=three&amp;amp;creator=4129988&amp;amp;i=3031109&#34;&gt;3D Cubes&lt;/a&gt; by Zach Bogart from &lt;a href=&#34;https://thenounproject.com/&#34;&gt;the Noun Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
